Sayan Banerjee

Data Science and Analytics Masters Student

A passionate and dedicated Data Science and Analytics enthusiast currently pursuing a Master's degree. Ex-System Engineer with 2+ years of experience in building data-intensive web applications. Proficient in Python programing, SQL and NoSQL database management, Azure cloud services, data analysis and machine learning.

sayan.tubai@gmail.com



+44 7407616126



Leeds, UK



github.com/sayan97

EDUCATION

MSc Data Science and Analytics

University of Leeds

09/2023 - Present

Leeds, UK

BTech Computer Science and Engineering

Institute of Engineering and Management (IEM)

2016 - 2020 Kolkata, India

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer (MES Designer)

Tata Consultancy Services

10/2020 - 08/2023

Kolkata

Tasks

- Set up Manufacturing Execution System(MES) web application and it's system functionalities for employee usage, or ensure proper installation of custom codes and appropriate software to enable proper functioning of the MES web application.
- o Configure MES application to align with the manufacturing processes and workflows of the organization. Customize MES modules, such as production planning, scheduling, quality management, and shop floor control.
- Set up the Azure Kubernetes Environment, including creating and configuring the Kubernetes cluster, deploying necessary resources, and ensuring scalability and availability.
- Analyse manufacturing data generated by MES and create business intelligence reports to support different business needs.
- Establish monitoring mechanisms to track the performance and health of the MES system. Implement proactive maintenance procedures to ensure system stability and address any issues that arise.
- Plan and execute the deployment of the MES application in the Azure Kubernetes Environment. Coordinate with operations teams for a smooth transition from existing systems to the new environment.
- Integrate MES application with other manufacturing systems, such as ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) systems, SCADA (Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition) systems, and IoT (Internet of Things) devices. Ensure smooth data exchange and communication between systems.

Machine Learning Intern

iNeuron.ai

04/2023 - 06/2023

Tasks

- Build full stack machine learning web application using Python and Flask.
- Deploy the complete application with CI/CD pipeline on cloud (Heroku/AWS/Azure).

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Store Sales Prediction

- Web application that uses machine learning regression model to predict the sales of a product in different stores based on different features present in BigMart dataset
- GitHub: https://github.com/sayan97/Store-Sales-prediction

Forest Fire Prediction

- Web application that uses machine learning classification model to predict the possibility of a forest fire based on different features present in Algerian Forest
- o GitHub: https://github.com/sayan97/Algerian-Forrest-Fire

Flipkart Review Scrapper

- Web application that can scrap reviews of any product from Flipkart (an ecommerce website).
- o GitHub: https://github.com/sayan97/Review-Scrapper-Flipkart

Leave Management System

- Web application that allows employees to apply for leaves and check their leave status and system admins to add, remove or update employee's information and approve or reject their leave requests.
- mySQL database is used to store employee information.
- GitHub: https://github.com/sayan97/Leave-Management-System

PDF Merger using Python:

- Desktop application that helps to merge multiple PDF files from a given directory into a single PDF file.
- GitHub: https://github.com/sayan97/iNeuron-Assignments/tree/main/PDF%20Merger

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Data Science - iNeuron.ai

Introduction to Artificial Intelligence - Coursera

Machine Learning using Python - Globsyn Business School

Data Structures and Algorithms using Python - NPTEL

MTA: Database Fundamentals - Microsoft

LANGUAGES KNOWN

Fnalish

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency